Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
So Balun's on the other side, huh?
Wasn't this supposed to be a lighthouse?
Yeah.
It surprised us, too. We had no idea Balun was a warp network's hub station.
But with it, we can head straight for the Large Magellanic Cloud.
It won't be that easy. This is enemy tech, after all.
Yeah...
Of course, Misaki was a bigger surprise.
I can't believe she was being possessed by an Iscandarian.
Will Misaki be able to return to normal?
With her help, we managed to get the gate control system back on line.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Show me your gratitude with action, not words.
We're loading a simplified version of the system onto a captured Garmillas fighter.
It's a dangerous mission... Who will be the Balun recon pilot?
The fighter squad captain will choose. I'll notify you once it's been decided.
I wish they'd picked me.
Don't covet all the glory.
Come back soon, okay?
Hey, you guys!
It's been decided, so scram!
Bye.
Good luck.
Don't screw up.
Back to your stations!
We were just trying to cheer him up.
Hey, Shinohara...
Yes, sir?
Try to relax a little.
I'm surprised.
Volunteering for this kind of mission isn't like you.
What are you thinking?
A long time ago... When I was still a trainee.
I saw one of our fighters flying, and it was so beautiful.
I don't know how to put it...
It was just flying, high overhead... But it was strong and noble.
And at that time, I thought it was the most beautiful thing in the world.
I later heard that it was a recon plane.
You know, I actually wanted to be in recon...
Huh?
Let me tell you one thing.
A recon pilot's job is to return.
So be sure you do. Got it?
Goergametsch, take off.
The Field Marshal will soon arrive.
Escort fleet, to your positions.
Repeat, the Field Marshal will soon arrive.
Five seconds until Geschtam Jump.
Three, two, one...
We have arrived at Balun on time.
The Goergametsch requests permission to come alongside.
I suppose that's Goer.
Yes.
Thank you for coming to this isolated location.
I am so honored that you've decided to hold such a huge naval review at Balun.
Even now, more ships gather—
The Empire is in greater peril than ever before.
And it falls to me to bring it together!
Three hours?
That's correct.
He has to recon the area, and locate the Magellanic gate in a mere three hours?
He's agreed to it.
Agreed?
If we can't use the gate, we have to leave as quickly as possible.
So when time runs out, we're leaving immediately?!
Sword 3 to control.
Ready to launch.
Permission granted.
Sword 3, roger.
See you soon.
Taking off.
Beginning phase 1.
We've lost Sword 3's physical signal.
It's been isolated from normal space.
Navigation Officer, give me the plan for our last chance to use the gate.
Yes, sir.
When time expires, we leave at once, without waiting for Sword 3.
This place is pretty crazy...
Garmillans?
What?
Nothing on radar, huh?
All I can rely on...
...is this, huh?
That call sign?
His choice.
Sword 3 was a call sign used by the 343rd Squadron.
I never thought I'd hear it out here.
You always said it was part of recon's job to return, but...
Brother...
Shinohara will be fine.
He'll come back.
He definitely will.
Approaching gate. Entering phase 2.
Brace for shock.
Huh? Seriously?!
43rd Milky Way Theater Carrier Strike Group, move to designated area.
The 124th Torpedo Squadron is now arriving.
Upon arrival, all ships are to move to designated positions.
Repeat, upon arrival, all ships are to move to designated positions.
I didn't think I'd survive that...
A-Are these...
Are all these Garmillans?
How is the Imperial Marshal doing?
He's so happy, I can read it in his coded message.
It sounds like he's feeling like a king.
So this is no mere astro naval review. Contact me if there are any issues.
But of course... Loyalty is my life!
Delheid theater forces now arriving.
This is the 66th Astro Corps, from Zelloom.
What a splendid sight...
This dignity, this power... This is Garmillas!
What are they all doing here?
Ten thousand... No, maybe more.
The Magellanic gate?
What is this?
An artificial object at the planet's center?
Okay...
<Unidentified Czvarke!>
<What is your squad!?>
<Watch your formation!>
<We're in the midst of a review!>
Oh, that got them mad...
Sorry, but I have things to do too!
minutes
Bring secondary engines on line.
No!
We will prepare to leave area.
<This is the patrol squad.>
<We are in pursuit of a suspicious, unidentified craft.>
<Understood. Permission to fire granted.>
Out of the way!
I'm going to be like they were!
Fly strong, fly noble... Fly beautiful!
Fly...
Moving to phase 3.
Wow, look at this thing...
So how's Shinohara doing?
Luckily, his wounds were minor, and he was otherwise unhurt.
We'll give him a thorough physical when he wakes up, but...
"Eh, don't worry,"
the doctor said.
This is the data he retrieved.
An artificial object at the center?
Yes, Balun is an artificial planet, with a central energy plant to power the gate.
Fortunately, we've confirmed that the Magellanic gate is functional.
But the problem is,
that the Garmillans have an enormous force of over ten thousand ships there.
That's...
It's impossible.
We have already plotted our other course.
Captain, we should change plans, and leave immediately.
No.
We hold our course.
Our best chance is to go straight through them.
Proud soldiers of Garmillas, and my courageous friends...
I have sad and painful news for you, who carry the glory of Garmillas.
Indeed...
Our Empire's noble ruler, our great Leader, Abelt Desler, has passed away!
As our nation faces this peril, who must lead us next?
My soul shakes at this great task.
As I share in this sorrow with you...
Here and now, I vow to you!
I shall carry out our great Leader's will,
and bring justice to the central government criminals who conceal his death.
If you would fight with me, then rise.
Wipe out the criminals who infest the government in Baleras!
All of them, without mercy! We must not...
What?
What is this?!
Something is at the galactic theater gate. A foreign ship has entered the area.
The gate is opening.
Combat speed 1.
Open fire!
The Terron ship is breaking through the 6th Army,
heading for Balun.
What luck...
This is a message from the gods,
that I should destroy the Yamato.
Open fire!
As a gift to our fallen Leader, sink the horrid Terron ship.
Ghale Garmillon!
Maintain heading.
Increase speed.
Increasing speed... Black 20.
This is how Admiral Okita fights.
Allies are between us! We can't fire at the Terron ship!
Don't let them fire with so many ships around!
We're losing more ships!
What are you doing? The ships are too close!
Split them!
No!
Surround and crush it.
But then our ships...
I don't care.
History is only made through sacrifice.
But...
All ships, change course! Don't be afraid...
Strength through numbers!
Concentrate fire forward.
Tear a hole through them!
Enemy ships are closing!
Shield on port side, breached!
Lower the bulkheads.
Gun turrets, report!
Damage control.
We're caught in Balun's gravity well!
Terron ship has been sunk. It's crashing on Balun.
Calculating crash point.
Mel-106, nar-68.
The Yamato has perished at Balun.
Had you been unable to sink that ship,
you'd have embarrassed the name of the wolf, Domel.
You're in a good mood, Zoellik.
Y-You...
I was so very moved by your speech.
Lord Desler!
That's impossible!
Your ship sank...
You are quite a stupid man.
Then, it was a double that died?
Cerestella was well aware of your assassination plot...
You've saved me from a very boring trip.
Now, then... Your crimes are clear.
But have you any final words, Zoel—
No... It's not true!
My fellows,
I only took on the mantle of traitor out of love for my country...
Goer, you fool...
Sir!
Traitor.
General Goer!
What is it?
Something's rising near Balun's equator!
It's the Yamato! The Yamato is climbing!
What?!
All crew to battle stations!
Wave Motion Gun is on line.
Increase engine power. Seal emergency vents.
Adjust course 180 degrees.
Open the firing vent.
Activate force injector.
Activation confirmed.
Releasing safety.
Pressure rising in chamber.
Adjust ship heading.
Target locked.
Ready to disable gravity anchor.
Fire Wave Motion Gun!
That gun of theirs...
Those idiots. What are they aiming at?
Emergency! Emergency!
Balun energy core is out of control! It's going to explode!
N-No!
R-Retreat!
Get out of this system now!
Disable gravity anchor. All crew, brace for impact.
The Large Magellanic Cloud.
Yeah, that's the Large Magellanic Cloud.
We made it, didn't we?
I've returned... To my own sea of stars.
Episode 18
Over the Black Light
No matter how steep or far the road is
I will not give up
Endless tears flowing down my cheek are not
A white flag of surrender
I go and become the wings of a loved one
Gather up the shattered dream
And take it to the end of the universe
Steady as she goes!
Row strongly
And hold your thoughts close to your chest
Steady as she goes!
Through your despair
A ray of light shines
They arrive at the distant Large Magellanic Cloud.
The Space Wolf is unleashed.
His eyes are like fire, his fangs like swords.
Each wields their knowledge against the other to further their ends.
Next time: They're Coming!
There are 246 days left before humanity is extinct.